Guide to the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
5488 B
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
669 linear feet.
Correspondence, Rule books, Agreements, etc.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
Subjects:
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted. Please contact the Kheel Center Reference Archivist for access information.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This forms a portion of collection #5488 B. The guide to the entire collection is available here.
Series II is arranged in 64 sub-series by Union file number.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series II. STATUES FOR THE GOVERNMENT OF LODGES (LOCAL LODGE LAWS)
  - Sub-Series 201-0. Local Lodge Laws
    - General, 1935-1959 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Various. Unofficial, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      Dec. 10, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 201-1. Local Lodge Laws
    - Lodge officers, how chosen. eligibility to office, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      Jan. 1, 1958.
    - Lodge officers, how chosen. eligibility to office, 1946-1957 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      July 1946-Dec. 31, 1957.
    - Legislative representatives, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      Nov. 22, 1932.
    - Lodge officers, how chosen. eligibility to office, 1934-1946 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      1934-June 1946.
    - Lodge Officers. How chosen, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Feb. 16, 1928.
  - Sub-Series 201-2. Local Lodge Laws
    - Eligibility to Membership, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Eligibility to Membership, 1951-1957 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Sept. 1951-Dec. 31, 1957.
    - Eligibility to Membership, 1946-1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      1946-Aug. 1951.
    - Eligibility to Membership, 1941-1945 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Eligibility to Membership, 1933-1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Eligibility to Membership, 1924-1932 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 201-3. Local Lodge Laws
    - Officer bonds, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      1925 June 20
    - Officers' bonds, 1940-1947 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 201-4. Local Lodge Laws
    - Election of officers, 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Aug. 1957-59.
    - Election of officers, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      1956-July 1957.
    - Election of officers, 1953-1955 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Dec. 1953-55.
    - Election of officers, 1951-1953 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Dec. 1951-Nov. 1953.
    - Election of officers, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      1949-Nov. 1951.
    - Election of officers, 1944-1948 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Election of officers, 1933-1943 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Election of officers, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      Dec. 29, 1932.
    - Election of officers, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Oct. 29, 1924.
  - Sub-Series 201-5. Local Lodge Laws
    - Religion and politics, 1930-1959 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Religion and politics, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      Nov. 7, 1925.
  - Sub-Series 201-6. Local Lodge Laws
    - Funds, 1925-1956 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Sub-Series 201-7. Local Lodge Laws
    - Surrender of charter, 1925-1959 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Sub-Series 201-8. Local Lodge Laws
    - Suspensions, 1954-1959 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      Sept. 1954-59.
    - Suspensions, 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      1951-Aug. 1954.
    - Suspensions, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      Feb. 12, 1932.
    - Suspensions, 1933-1950 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series 201-9. Local Lodge Laws
    - Election to Membership, 1949-1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Election to Membership, 1921-1948 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series 201-10. Local Lodge Laws
    - Meetings at different points, 1925-1951 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series 201-11. Local Lodge Laws
    - Trials, 1955-1959 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Trials, 1950-1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      April 1950-54.
    - Trials, 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      1948-March 1950.
    - Trials, 1946-1947 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Nov. 1946-47.
    - Trials, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      1944-Nov. 1946.
    - 201-11(a). Charges and trials. Lodge 890-Cincinnati, Ohio, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Trials, 1941-1943 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - 201-11(b). Trials, 1934-1940 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Trials. Mrs. Margaret Kitten, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Trials, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Trials, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Trials, 1937-1940 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Trials. Timmons vs. Bane, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Trials. Lodge 1192 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Trials. Lodge 1192 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Trials. 1937-38 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Trials. Lodge 890-Cincinnati, Ohio, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      Nov. 30, 1943.
  - Sub-Series 201-12. Local Lodge Laws
    - Fees and dues, 1948-1959 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      May 1948-59.
    - Fees and dues, 1940-1948 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      1940-April 1948.
    - Fees and dues, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Fees and dues, 1933-1939 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Dues, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Nov. 16, 1932.
    - Dues, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Dues, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Oct. 3, 1930.
    - Lodge assessments, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Dec.24, 1927.
  - Sub-Series 201-13. Local Lodge Laws
    - Meeting halls, 1931-1949 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Meeting hall, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Jan. 31, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 201-14. Local Lodge Laws
    - Holding more than one office 1933-34 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Holding more than one office, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Holding more than one office, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Holding more than one office, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      Dec. 30, 1930.
  - Sub-Series 201-15. Local Lodge Laws
    - Qualification of Lodge officers, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      Jan. 1 1958.
    - Qualification of Lodge officers, 1951-1959 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      Oct. 1951-Dec. 31, 1959.
    - Qualification of Lodge officers, 1933-1951 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Dec. 1933- Sept. 1951.
    - Qualification of Lodge officers, 1929-1933 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      1929-Nov. 1933.
  - Sub-Series 201-16. Local Lodge Laws
    - Membership in other labor organizations, 1933-1953 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Membership in other labor organizations, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      1930 March 20
  - Sub-Series 201-17. Local Lodge Laws
    - Presiding officer, 1957-1959 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      July 1957-59.
    - Presiding officer, 1951-1957 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      1951-June 1957.
    - Presiding officer, 1933-1950 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Presiding officer, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Presiding officer, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      1926 May 22
  - Sub-Series 201-18. Local Lodge Laws
    - Duties-Board of Trustees, 1922-1959 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series 201-19. Local Lodge Laws
    - Violation-laws of principles, 1924-1959 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 201-20. Local Lodge Laws
    - Special cases-obligation, 1951-1958 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Special cases-obligation, 1935-1950 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Special instances-Obligation of candidates, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      Feb. 13, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 201-21. Local Lodge Laws
    - Quorum, 1927-1959 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Sub-Series 201-23. Local Lodge Laws
    - Installation of officers, 1924-1957 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Sub-Series 201-24. Local Lodge Laws
    - Vacancies-how filled, 1933-1959 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Dec. 31, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Sub-Series 201-25. Local Lodge Laws
    - Membership rights, 1930-1957 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Sub-Series 201-26. Local Lodge Laws
    - Strike breakers, 1924-1951 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 201-27. Local Lodge Laws
    - Investment of Lodge funds, 1930-1959 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series 201-28. Local Lodge Laws
    - Form of preferring charges, 1925-1957 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Sub-Series 201-30. Local Lodge Laws
    - Legality of meetings without charter being present, 1932-1938 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Charter at meetings, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Aug. 8, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 201-32. Local Lodge Laws
    - Special meetings, 1925-1947 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 201-33. Local Lodge Laws
    - Circulars, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 201-31. Local Lodge Laws
    - Jurisdiction, 1930-1933 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 201-34. Local Lodge Laws
    - Order of business, 1925-1956 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 201-35. Local Lodge Laws
    - Associate Membership, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Oct. 3, 1925.
  - Sub-Series 201-36. Local Lodge Laws
    - Organization committee, 1926-1949 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 201-37. Local Lodge Laws
    - Voting rights of members, 1931-1958 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Voting rights of members, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Nov. 30, 1928.
  - Sub-Series 201-39. Local Lodge Laws
    - Duties of Lodge officers, 1927-1954 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 201-38. Local Lodge Laws
    - Membership in more than one Lodge, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Jan. 9, 1930.
  - Sub-Series 201-40. Local Lodge Laws
    - Bylaws, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      Nov. 6, 1959.
    - Bylaws, 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 17)
      April 1956-Nov 5, 1959.
    - Bylaws, 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      July 1955-March 1956.
    - Bylaws, 1953-1955 (Box 11, Folder 19)
      June 1953-July 1955.
    - Bylaws, 1952-1953 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      April 1952-May 1953.
    - Bylaws, 1950-1952 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      April 1950-March 1952.
    - Bylaws, 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 22)
      Oct. 1948-March 1950.
    - Bylaws, 1933-1948 (Box 11, Folder 23)
      1933-Sept. 30, 1948.
    - Election of Lodge officers, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 24)
      Nov. 23, 1927.
  - Sub-Series 201-42. Local Lodge Laws
    - Minutes of Lodge meetings, 1928-1958 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series 201-43. Local Lodge Laws
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges. Lodge Nos. 924-928, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1945-1958 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1935-1944 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - 201-43(d). Construction of laws for government of local Lodges, 1941-1943 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges. Transfer of Elmer E. Quinn from Lodge no. 3 (Omaha, Nebraska) to Lodge no. 205 (Falls City, Nebraska), 1941-1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Construction of laws for the government of local Lodges, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      1929 April 17
    - Appeal to the Grand Executive Council Session of July, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Series 201-44. Local Lodge Laws
    - Audit by Board of trustees, 1936-1953 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 201-45. Local Lodge Laws
    - Right of Appeal, 1955-1959 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Right of Appeal, 1949-1954 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Right of Appeal, 1929-1948 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 201-46. Local Lodge Laws
    - Recall, 1931-1957 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 201-47. Local Lodge Laws
    - Regular Meetings, 1929-1958 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 201-48. Local Lodge Laws
    - Failure of Lodge officers to attend meetings, 1930-1958 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series 201-50. Local Lodge Laws
    - Lodge Officers. How classified, 1935-1948 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series 201-51. Local Lodge Laws
    - Legal meetings, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 201-52. Local Lodge Laws
    - Right to perform official duties while under charges, 1932-1933 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 201-53. Local Lodge Laws
    - Tenure of office legislative representatives, 1932-1954 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Series 201-54. Local Lodge Laws
    - Qualifications of legislative representatives, 1932-1957 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Sub-Series 201-55. Local Lodge Laws
    - Duties of legislative representatives, 1933-1957 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 201-56. Local Lodge Laws
    - Copy of Lodge audits to System Boards, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Sub-Series 201-57. Local Lodge Laws
    - Combining or separating local Lodge offices, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Sub-Series 201-58. Local Lodge Laws
    - Resignation of Membership, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Sub-Series 201-59. Local Lodge Laws
    - Lodges with ten or fewer members, 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Sub-Series 201-66. Local Lodge Laws
    - Misappropriation of funds, 1936-1959 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 201-61. Local Lodge Laws
    - Re-admission of expelled member (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series 201-49. Local Lodge Laws
    - Letter from recording ceremony to Grand President, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series 201-62. Local Lodge Laws
    - Fines for non-attendance at Lodge meetings, 1947-1959 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series 201-63. Local Lodge Laws
    - Preservation of Lodge records, 1948-1956 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 201-64. Local Lodge Laws
    - Special assessments of Lodges, 1957-1964 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      Sept. 1957-64.
    - Special assessments by Lodges, 1949-1957 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      1949-Sept. 1957.
  - Sub-Series 201-65. Local Lodge Laws
    - Duties of financial secretary, 1951-1957 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Sub-Series 201-66. Local Lodge Laws
    - Salaries of Lodge officers, 1951-1957 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Sub-Series 201-67. Local Lodge Laws
    - Membership application, 1952-1956 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Sub-Series 201-68. Local Lodge Laws
    - Sick and welfare funds, 1953-1959. (Box 12, Folder 33)
      1953-59..